What's going on, man? Good to
see you, brother. Good to see you.
I'm pretty good. Not too bad. Not too bad.
Who am I here with today?
Justin Waller.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Five in a year.
Do you come from money?
Fuck no. Hell no, man. No. Not at all. I
grew up in South Louisiana. There was no money around.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Fucking right. You drop me butt naked in any
city in America, I'd be hanging still in six weeks.
How can somebody become a
multi-millionaire like yourself in today's world?
Hard Knocks Family. We just landed in Miami, Florida, and we're
about to go meet up with and interview the legend Justin Waller.
For those of you who don't know, Justin owns
one of the largest construction companies across the United States,
and he's quickly became one of the
most renowned entrepreneurs in the entire business world.
So we're going to go meet up with Justin and ask
him how he was able to grow such a massive company
and his best advice to everyone
watching trying to become millionaires in 2024.
So with that being said, let's
go see what Justin has to say.
All right, you guys. So we're on
the way now to meet up with Justin.
We're pulling up shortly. I can't wait for the
game that I know that he's about to deliver.
This is going to be a million
dollars worth of game from Justin Waller.
Pulling up here in a second.
I can't wait for this one.
What's going on, man? Good to
see you, brother. Good to see you.
Good. Not too bad. Not too bad.
Who am I here with today?
Justin Waller.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Yeah, so I started off in steel. I
was 24 and started hanging steel locally in Louisiana.
Now we have over 200 men, coast
to coast, California to New York, Caribbean.
We'll put steel up on the moon.
How long have you been in construction for?
I've been in construction 15 years.
Until next March.
How important has that focus been?
Becoming an expert as opposed to trying
to diversify and jump from industry to industry.
How important has it become for you becoming a master,
one of the best in the world at one thing?
Yeah, I think if I would give my young self credit
for anything, it would be that I stayed in the same fight.
A lot of people, they go into a career, they start
getting banged up a little bit, and then they change directions.
But what they don't understand is they're going
to take the beginner's licks of that new industry.
So if I did anything right, even though the model might not
have been the model that I think ultimately I'll end up in,
I stayed in the same thing long
enough to make substantial money to create freedom.
If you can create freedom, then you can go.
You can go start watering other plants.
You see, we only get so much energy in life.
And so you have this cup
of water, let's call it your energy.
If you pour it over too many plants,
you'll never bear fruit on any of them.
So the one thing I did right was stay
in the same industry for a very, very long time.
And now I can branch out, do other things, grow other businesses, look
at other business models that might be better off in the long run.
And do you come from money?
Fuck no.
Hell no, man.
No, not at all.
I grew up in South Louisiana.
There was no money around, I can tell you.
So what was that turning point like for you?
Like, how did you know
you wanted to get really serious?
About becoming financially free and
building that long-term generational wealth?
What was the turning point like for you?
Well, I think what happens is when you're in
a situation, any situation, and this is not uncommon,
you either become the situation
that you're in the atmosphere,
or you decide that you want to
do anything but be in that atmosphere.
So for me, it was a pretty easy decision to make
that I just wanted to find out what else was out there.
I knew what I didn't want.
And so it put me on this
path to finding more and more consciousness.
And as I come across those things
in my growth and whatever I do,
as far as the level of...
obtainment of my goals I hit,
every time I get to the top of
a mountain, I'm constantly looking for the next one.
And so I think there's two things.
You run away or decide not to
be what you were a part of.
And then two, on that path, you find more
consciousness, which kind of controls your direction you go.
And once you identify those things and you identify that
you can do those things and you get on that path,
generally the happiness is on the climbing part.
Just make sure you're looking for the next one to climb because you can
get in trouble if you get to the top and you have nowhere to go.
Hard Knocks family, we're about to get right back to
the interview, but I have a very special announcement to make.
We just launched.
The official community for the School of Hard
Knocks, otherwise known as the School of Mentors.
In this community, you will have access to hop on
live calls with the multimillionaires we interview every single week.
You'll be able to ask them questions
about your career, your life and your business.
You'll also get access to
exclusive unreleased content and masterclasses.
We've been filming with the
world's most successful business owners.
You do not want to miss out on this.
So click the link in the description
below to join the School of Mentors today.
We can't wait to see you on the inside.
And with that being said,
let's get back to the interview.
We have a lot of money to start this.
How did you get the money to start this business?
No, man, we didn't have any money.
So what I had to do is go out and get contracts and then go
to the bank and show them I had contracts and try to get lines of credit.
My first line of credit was for $15,000.
I'll never forget it because my payrolls were like
$2,500 a week because I had like two guys maybe.
And we were doing backyard buildings.
And so I always say about when it when it comes to dealing with the
banks, always go to the banks when you're solvent and you have a lot of money.
But in the case that you don't have
a lot of money, that's what an entrepreneur does.
He figures it out. So I
took my contracts that I had won.
And then I went to the bank.
And showed them that I had a contract and they gave me
a little loan against it to get me through the first couple.
What is the secret to being able to leverage capital
to leverage that good debt and turn that into wealth ultimately?
So if you look at the real
estate, I own over 400 doors now.
So you can underwrite a deal, understand the capital stack, whether you're raising somebody else's money to get
the down payment and then you're going to take it to the long term debt with the bank.
You just have to be able
to understand the math of real estate.
You know, what's the net operating income?
What's the cap rate?
What's my debt service going to be?
Where are we at in the cycle on that property?
So one thing I look at
very hard right now, we're buying properties.
Like a lot of people don't want to buy
properties right now because the interest rate is so high.
And the only fear that I would have is that we get to the end of a five
to seven year arm and we're in a 1980 situation where you go from 7.5% or 8% to 16.
But if you're if you understand the
math of real estate, it's very simple.
In fact, I'd even say it's third grade math.
Then you understand the debt service and you understand where you are
in the overall cycle, like the long term, short term debt cycle.
And you're paying attention to where rates will go.
You should have enough time to make decisions.
You should have enough time to make decisions
that will allow you to reduce that risk.
You can't get away from it completely, but you should massively be able to
reduce the risk and set your properties up the way they need to be.
You know, they don't teach that in school, right?
I've heard they don't teach that in school.
And why would they?
Because the system is built for us to spit out
employees and people that say yes and they pay taxes.
They get married, they buy a
three bedroom house and they die.
And so, no, I don't think they're going to
be teaching cap rates in school any time soon.
Right. Ben Franklin said that most people die
at 22, but they're buried when they're 70.
That's right. That's right. I heard
that exact quote the other day.
I think I heard 30 and 80.
But nonetheless, yeah, there's a bunch
of dead men walking every day.
They don't live free. They can't say what they want.
They want to say things, they feel things.
And I think that's why people resonate with us so much is that
we're getting to speak on their behalf because we're free enough to talk.
Hard times right now, but
we're going to turn it around.
America is going to turn it around.
We're going to get the
right guy in the White House.
Absolutely. And then when that happens, we've got to
be able to clean things up a little bit.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Oh, single year?
Five in a year.
Five million dollars. That's just for yourself.
Yeah, just no, that's take home.
You know, that's complete take home.
Yeah.
How about for the businesses?
Businesses, we've got up to 35.
35 million dollars.
Yeah.
How did you scale from seven to eight figures?
Two things, it's systems and
then it's competent people with intent.
So if you take intention and then you take competency, their
ability to do it, that means they want to and they can.
If you can put those two things together
and have them help you build the systems out.
And I say help you very intentfully because a lot of times if you make a plan and you hand it to
somebody, they have no ownership, which means they're sitting in the boat with their arms crossed waiting for it to go wrong.
But if they can help you build
systems and be a part of building something.
Then they can have ownership in it.
And when they can have ownership
in it, they can get behind it.
So intention, competency and the ability to be a part and have autonomy in a company
is going to take you a long way when it comes to dealing with employees and staff.
And then one last thing, make sure you manage from a place of
I should be paying you more money, not you should be making me richer.
If I can jump somebody's ass because I should be writing them
a bigger bonus check, then we're in a very, very healthy place.
Because in that way, you've created an entrepreneur inside the business
and you are grading them on performance based off of things.
And that's what I mean by that.
And then the other thing is that you can have a vision
that should align with something that is valuable to them as well.
And that's making more money, having a better future for themselves
and being able to see a vision that can fit inside yours.
What's the best advice that
you've ever got from a mentor?
My favorite quote is that you can tell the
size of a man by the size of his problems.
If you can learn to embrace the things that are
getting in your way, embrace the failures that are coming.
Those are just small bricks that are
going to build your castle in life.
Every time you fail, you must be grateful for it.
And see it as a part of a story.
Whether it's on a podcast, on a yacht, on a boat, on a
plane, or in a restaurant of how you became the man that you are.
And if you don't have any of those stories,
nobody will be interested in your story at all.
And it'll mean nothing.
So start to take pride in the negative things that happen to you because those
are the things that are going to make you the man that you're going to become.
For every new level, there's a new devil.
Every king's got scars, cowboy.
That's crazy.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Fucking right.
You drop me butt naked in any city
in America, I'll be hanging still in six weeks.
So you go right back into steel.
And that's what's most important.
If you stick to the same thing,
you're going to make it all back.
That's what's most important.
If you keep doing the same thing again and again and
again and again, you get a superpower that many people don't understand.
And it's that nobody can
ever take it away from me.
I know for a fact I could go
anywhere and be hanging still in six weeks.
How old are you now?
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
Last message to the younger generation.
They want to get Justin Waller rich in today's world.
How can somebody become a
multi-millionaire like yourself in today's world?
You can tell the size of a
man by the size of his problems.
Get up every day, every time
you get hit in the face.
Have a relentless heart.
And there's nothing this world can't stop you from doing.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you.
That was phenomenal.
That's a wrap on today's video, guys.
Justin Waller just went crazy.
But I want you to like and subscribe
for amazing content we've got coming very, very soon.
And as I mentioned earlier, we just launched
our official community for the School of Hard Knocks.
So to get connected to and learn directly from the millionaires that
we interview every single week, click the link down in the description below.
And we'll see you on the inside.
The School of Mentors, we can't wait to have you.
We'll see you in the next video.